<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The cause why Adam &amp; Eve were driven out of paradice and the Jews out of their own land of Canaan by George Fox.</title>
            <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1683</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 38 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 10 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A40131</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing F1758</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R30467</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11326784</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11326784</idno>
            <idno type="VID">47472</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A40131)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 47472)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1460:49)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The cause why Adam &amp; Eve were driven out of paradice and the Jews out of their own land of Canaan by George Fox.</title>
                  <author>Fox, George, 1624-1691.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 14 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Benjamin Clark ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1683.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Harvard University Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Society of Friends --  Doctrines.</term>
               <term>Theology, Doctrinal.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02</date>
            <label>Ali Jakobson</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:47472:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:47472:1"/>
            <p>THE CAUSE WHY Adam &amp; Eve Were driven out of PARADICE, AND THE JEWS Out of their own <hi>Land of Canaan,</hi>
            </p>
            <p>By <hi>GEORGE FOX.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Benjamin Clark,</hi> in <hi>George-Yard</hi> in <hi>Lombard-ſtreet.</hi> 1683.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:47472:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:47472:2"/>
            <head>The cauſe why <hi>Adam</hi> and <hi>Eve</hi> were driven out of Paradice, and the Jews out of their own Land of <hi>Canaan.</hi>
            </head>
            <p n="1">1. <hi>Here you may ſee the Cauſe of</hi> Adam <hi>and</hi> Eve <hi>being drove out of Paradiſe.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="2">2. <hi>And the Cauſe of the deſtruction of the Old World.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="3">3. <hi>And the Cauſe of confounding</hi> Nimrod <hi>and his Company.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="4">4. <hi>And the Cauſe of the Jews going ſo often into Captivity.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And the deſtructions that came ſo often upon them.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And the confuſion that is and hath been among the Chriſtians, where all may Read, Hear and Fear, that they take warning and turn from ſuch evils, leſt the Judgments of God come upon you that came upon</hi> Adam <hi>and</hi> Eve, <hi>and the Old World, and the Jews, and their Fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fathers that diſobeyed God and Chriſt, and the good Spirit that he gave them: for no unclean thing ſhall enter into the Paradice and Kingdom of God, not into the holy City new</hi> Jeruſalem, <hi>though the unclean do enter into the great City of the Whore of</hi> Babylon.</p>
            <p>Adam <hi>and</hi> Eve <hi>were driven out of Paradice for their diſobedience.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And for diſobedience</hi> Cains <hi>ſtock, and the Old World were de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroyed.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>For diſobedience</hi> Nimrod <hi>and his Company were confounded and Scattered.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And for diſobedience the Jews were drove and carried Captive out of their own Land of</hi> Canaan.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And for diſobedience to the ſame Light, Power and Holy Ghoſt, that the Apoſtles and the Church were in in the Apoſtles daies, the Chriſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans in name and not in power and nature, are without the heavenly holy City New</hi> Jeruſalem: <hi>An unjuſt man is an abomination to the Juſt, and he that is upright in the way, is an abomination to the wicked,</hi> Prov. 29.27. <hi>In God I will praiſe his Word, in God will I put my
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:47472:3"/>truſt: I will not fear what fleſh can do unto me,</hi> Pſal. 56.4. <hi>Thus ſaith the Lord, I will feed them that oppreſs thee with their own fleſh, and they ſhall be drunk with their own blood as with ſweet Wine, and all ſhall know that I am the Lord,</hi> Iſa. 49.26.</p>
            <p>THe Lord God is holy and pure, therefore he would have all his people to be holy and pure, and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore conſider what the Lord in the Old and New Teſtament Commands you to forſake, and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded that you ſhall not do. In <hi>Exodus</hi> the Lord ſaith, <hi>Thou ſhalt not Kill. Thou ſhalt not Steal. Thou ſhalt not bear falſe witneſs againſt thy Neighbour. Thou ſhalt not commit Adultery. Thou ſhalt not covet thy Neighbours Houſe, thou ſhalt not covet thy Neighbours Wife, nor his Man-ſervant, nor his Maid ſervant, nor his Ox, nor his Aſs, nor any thing that is thy Neighbours;</hi> theſe things are forbidden in <hi>Exod.</hi> 20. in the Old Teſtament, and much more in the New, for Chriſt ſaith, <hi>You have heard that it hath been ſaid of old time</hi> (to wit) in the Old Teſtament, <hi>Thou ſhalt not commit Adultery, but I ſay, whoſoever looketh on a woman to luſt after her, hath committed Adultery with her already in his heart;</hi> and here you may ſee the Law took hold of the outward act, and the Goſpel took hold of the inward act; <hi>For out of the heart pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeds the Evil thoughts, Murders, Adulteries, Fornications, Thefts, falſe Witneſſes, Blaſphemies, theſe are the things which defile a man,</hi> Mat. 5. &amp; Mat. 15.</p>
            <p>And theſe evil things are in Man and woman, yea, done or committed before they be acted outwardly: And therefore the Apoſtle ſaith in 2 <hi>Cor.</hi> 5. <hi>Every one ſhall give an account of things done in the body, for,</hi> ſaith he, <hi>we muſt all appear before the Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment Seat of Chriſt, that every one may receive the things done in his body, according to that he hath done, whether it be good or bad. Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing therefore the Terrour of the Lord, we perſwade men,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>To ſhun that which is bad and evil, and cleave to that which is good, and luſt not after Beauty in thy Heart, but keep thee from the evil woman; from the flattery of the Tongue of a ſtranger; neither let her take thee with her Eye-lids. For by means of a whoriſh woman, a man is brought to a piece of Bread: and the Adultereſs will hunt for thy precious life. But whoſo committeth Adultery with a woman, lacketh under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding: he that doth it, deſtroyeth his own ſoul, and a wound and
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:47472:3"/>diſhonour ſhall he get, and his reproach ſhall not be wiped away,</hi> Prov. 6. and you may ſee in <hi>Prov.</hi> 2. This <hi>ſtrange woman which flatters with her words, who forſaketh the guide of her youth</hi> the Spirit of God, <hi>and forgetteth the Covenant of her God. For her houſe en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clineth to death, and her paths unto the dead. None that goeth unto her returneth again, neither take they hold of the paths of life.</hi> And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore <hi>that thou maiſt walk in the way of good men, and keep in the paths of life,</hi> Prov. 2. This is the Exhortation of the wiſdom of God to follow; <hi>For the mouth of the ſtrange woman is a deep pit, and he that is abhorred of the Lord, ſhall fall therein,</hi> Prov. 22. And you may ſee in <hi>Prov.</hi> 5. how <hi>Solomon</hi> exhorts to the ſtudy of Wiſdom, and ſheweth the miſchief of Riot and Whoredom; and <hi>Prov.</hi> 7. how the filly <hi>young man, void of underſtanding, in the twilight in the evening, in the black and dark night</hi> how he was de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceived by the ſpeeches and attire of the Harlot, <hi>whoſe Houſe is the way to Hell, going down to the Chambers of Death:</hi> And this well<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>favoured Harlot deceived the young man under pretence of Reli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gion; for ſhe pretended, ſhe had Peace Offerings, and ſhe had paid her Vows, and the good man was gone from home; and this Whore abides not in her houſe, but is without in the ſtreets, and lyeth in wait at every corner; ſhe is out of her houſe from the ſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit of God, whored from that; and ſo Chriſt the good man is not within, and ſo that whoriſh ſpirits habitation is in the twilight and darkneſs, and would beget others either to ſpiritual Adultery, or carnal Adultery; one while this whoriſh ſpirit is loud and ſtub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>born, and another while with flattering Speeches, all that keeps with the ſpirit of God, and the light of Chriſt in their Hearts will keep out of her way that leads to Hell, <hi>and the Chambers of death.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>In <hi>Jer.</hi> 3. how <hi>Jeremiah</hi> complains againſt <hi>Judahs</hi> vile whore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom and committing Adultery, and <hi>Judah</hi> was worſe than back<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſliding <hi>Iſrael,</hi> who ſaid, <hi>She is gone upon every high Mountain, and under every green tree, and there hath played the Harlot. And thou haſt polluted the Land with thy whoredoms and thy wickedneſs, and thou haſt a wheres forehead, thou refuſeſt to be aſhamed.</hi> Here you may ſee what a ſad condition the Jews came into, when they forſook the Lord; and therefore let Chriſtians beware that they be not found in the ſame practice, and ſo come under the ſame Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, as you may read in <hi>Jer.</hi> 3. and 5. you may ſee the Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of God upon the Jews for perverſeneſs and Adultery, for
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:47472:4"/>the Lord ſaith, <hi>How ſhall I pardon for this, my Children have for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaken me, and ſworn by them that are no Gods; for when I had fed them to the full, then they committed Adultery, and aſſembled them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves by Troops into the Harlots Houſes. They were as fed Horſes in the morning, every one neighing after his Neighbours Wife: Shall not I viſit for theſe things, ſaith the Lord? Shall not my ſoul be avenged on ſuch a Nation as this? and the Prophets ſhall become wind; and the Word is not in them.</hi> Now let them that are called Chriſtians in Chriſtendom look to themſelves, and ſee if they be not found in this ſpiritual and natural whoredom that the Jews were found in, though they made a profeſſion of the Scriptures of the Old Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtament; and they that go under the name of Chriſtians, may make a profeſſion of the New Teſtament in words; but <hi>Jeremiah</hi> ſaith the Word was not in thoſe Jews that run into theſe wickedneſſes, neither is it in thoſe called Chriſtians that runs into ſpiritual or car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal whoredom, <hi>For the Word of God is a fire, and hammer, and a Sword to beat and cut down, and burn up the evil matter and its fruits.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And in <hi>Jer.</hi> 29.23. ſpeaking to the Jews, <hi>Becauſe they have committed Villany in Iſrael, and have committed Adultery with their Neighbours Wives, and have ſpoken lying words in my Name, which I have not commanded them, even I know and am a witneſs, ſaith the lord;</hi> therefore is their deſtruction foretold.</p>
            <p>And <hi>Jeremiah</hi> ſaith in Chap. 9. <hi>O that I had in the Wilderneſs a lodging place of away faring men, that I might leave my people, and go from them: for they be all Adulterers, an aſſembly of treacherous men. Their tongue is as an arrow ſhot out, it ſpeaketh deceit: one ſpeaketh peaceably to his Neighbour with his mouth, but in his heart he layeth wait for him. Shall not I viſit for theſe things? ſaith the Lord.</hi> And therefore ſaith the Lord, <hi>I will make</hi> Jeruſalem <hi>heaps, a den of Dragons;</hi> which was the chief City of worſhip amongſt the Jews; and did not the Lord bring his Judgments upon it?</p>
            <p>And <hi>Jeremiah</hi> ſaith, <hi>My heart is broken becauſe of the Prophets; and all my bones ſhake, and I am like a drunkenman, and like a man whom wine hath overcome, becauſe of the Lord, and becauſe of the Word of his holineſs, for the land is full of Adulteries: for becauſe of Swearing the land mourns,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>Their courſe is evil, and their forces not right. I have ſeen alſo in the Prophets of</hi> Jeruſalem <hi>a horrible thing, they commit Adultery, and walk in lies; they ſtrengthen alſo
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:47472:4"/>the hands of evil doers, that none doth return from their wickedneſs: they are all of them unto me as</hi> Sodom (to wit) the Lord, <hi>and the Inhabitants thereof as</hi> Gomorrah, Jer. 23. And <hi>Jeremiah</hi> ſaith, <hi>I have ſeen thine Adulteries, and thy neighings; the lewdeneſs of thy Whoredoms, and thine abominations on the hills in the fields. Wo be unto thee, O</hi> Jeruſalem, <hi>wilt not thou be made clean?</hi> Jer. 13. And again he ſaith, <hi>Thou haſt polluted the Land with thy Whoredoms, and with thy wickedneſs; and through the lightneſs of her whoredoms,</hi> to wit, the Jews, <hi>and committeſt Adultery with Stocks and Stones.</hi> Here you may ſee the carnal and ſpiritual Whoredom among the Jews, who were the greateſt Profeſſors of the Old Teſtament in their day, and yet the greateſt diſobeyers of God; let them that calls themſelves Chriſtians, be warned of their ſins, and of their Judgments. And the Lord ſaith, <hi>Will you ſteal and murder, and commit Adultery,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>and come and ſtand before me in this horſe, which is called by my name; and ſaying, The Temple of the Lord, the Temple of the Lord, and ſay we are delivered to do all theſe abomi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nations, this Houſe which is called by my name is become a den of Rob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers;</hi> ſo God rejected the vain confidence of the Jews, and the ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crifice of the diſobedient, <hi>Jer.</hi> 7.9.</p>
            <p>And <hi>Job</hi> ſpeaks againſt the Murderers and Adulterers, he ſaith, <hi>They are of thoſe that rebel againſt the light; they know not the waies thereof, nor abide in the paths thereof, the murderer riſes with the light, killeth the poor and needy, and in the night is as a Thief; The eyes of the Adulterer waiteth for the twilight, ſaying no eye ſhall ſee me, and diſguiſes his face in the dark. They dig through houſes which they had marked for themſelves in the day time; they know not the light, for the morning is to them as a ſhadow of death; then here was ſome terrour upon the Adulterers, if they were known; but as drought and heat conſumeth the Snow waters, ſo doth the Grave thoſe that have ſinned,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>The womb forgets him, the worms ſhall ſweet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly feed upon him, he ſhall be no more remembred, and wickedneſs ſhall be broaken as a tree,</hi> Job 24.15, &amp;c. See how loathſom wicked<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs and adultery was in days paſt. And <hi>Solomon</hi> ſaith in <hi>Prov.</hi> 23. <hi>For an Whore is a deep ditch, ſhe layeth in wait as for a prey, and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſeth the tranſgreſſors among men;</hi> and this by experience is ſeen.</p>
            <p>And <hi>Hoſea</hi> ſhews Gods Judgments upon the Jews for their ſpi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritual and carnal whoredom in the firſt Chapter; and further ſaith,
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:47472:5"/>
               <hi>By ſwearing and lying, and killing and ſtealing, and committing adul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tery, they break out, and blood touches blood: therefore ſhall the Land mourn, for wheredoms have cauſed them to err; they have gone a whoring from under their God, they have committed whoredom con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinually;</hi> read the Chapter throughout, and there you may ſee the abominations and wickedneſs of the Jews, and of their ſpiritual and carnal whoredom, whom God threatens with his Judgments; and in <hi>Hoſea</hi> 2. he ſaith, <hi>Let her therefore put away her whoredoms out of her ſight, and her Adulteries between her breaſts, leſt I ſtrip her naked, and ſet her as in the day ſhe was born; and make her as a wilderneſs, and ſet her like a dry Land, and ſlay her with thirſt; for the Lord ſaith, I will not have mercy upon her Children, for they be the Children of whoredoms. They are all Adulterers, as an Oven heated by the Baker, who ceaſeth from raiſing after he hath kneded the dough, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>til it be leavened,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>Hoſ.</hi> 7. where you may ſee Gods reproof and wrath againſt the manifold ſins of the Jews, throughout the whole Book; and therefore let all that goes under the name of Chriſtians, beware of theſe ſins of the Jews, leſt the wrath of God comes upon you. And the Lord ſent <hi>Iſaiah</hi> to reproove and declare againſt the Jews and their whoriſh Idolatry, and ſaith, <hi>The righteous periſheth, and no man layeth it to heart, and merciful men are taken away; none conſidering that the righteous are taken away from the evil to come. But draw near hither ye Sons of the Sorcereſs, the ſeed of the Adulterer, and the Whore, againſt whom do ye ſport your ſelves; againſt whom make ye a wide mouth, and draw out the tongue; are ye not Children of tranſgreſſion a ſeed of Falſhood,</hi> Iſa. 5.7.</p>
            <p>And <hi>David</hi> ſaith, <hi>Seeing thou hateſt inſtruction, and caſts my words behind thee. When thou ſaweſt a thief, then thou conſenteſt with him, and haſt been partaker with Adulterers; thou giveſt thy mouth to evil, and thy tongue foameth deceit.</hi> Unto ſuch wicked ones God ſaith, <hi>What haſt thou to do to declare my Statutes, or that thou ſhouldeſt take my Covenant in thy mouth,</hi> &amp;c <hi>Pſal.</hi> 50. ſo every one that names God and Chriſt, muſt depart from iniquity. And in <hi>Mal.</hi> 3. the Lord ſaith, <hi>I will come near to you to Judgment, and I will be a ſwift witneſs againſt the Sorcerer, and againſt the Adulterer, and falſe Swearer, and againſt thoſe that oppreſs the Hireling in his wages, and the Widow and the Fatherleſs, and that turn aſide a ſtranger from his right, and fear not me, ſaith the Lord of Hoſt.</hi> Here you may ſee
<pb facs="tcp:47472:5"/>
               <pb facs="tcp:47472:6"/>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:47472:6"/>God is both Witneſs againſt Wickedneſs, and the Judge of it.</p>
            <p>And <hi>Ezekiel</hi> the Lord ſent to pour out Judgments upon the Jews for their Adultery, and ſaid, That they were old in Adul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teries; and they went a whoring after the Heathen, and were polluted with their Idols, and had forgotten the Lord, and caſt him behind their backs; <hi>Through their lewdneſs and whoredoms they have committed Adultery, and blood is in their hands.</hi> And you may ſee the 23 Chapter throughout, <hi>They have commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted whoredoms in Egypt: they have committed whoredoms in their youth: there were their breaſts preſſed, and there they bruiſed the teats of their Virginity.</hi> O let all that are called by the name of Chriſtians have a care of this ſpiritual and car<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal whoredom, and <hi>Ezek.</hi> 6. <hi>I am broken, ſaith the Lord, with their whoriſh heart which hath departed from me,</hi> there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Lord threatens his Judgments upon them. And again, the Lord declareth againſt the Jews monſtrous whoredom and adultery, as you may ſee in the 16 Chapter throughout, they are compared through their lewdneſs and whoredom, and wickedneſs to <hi>Sodom.</hi> And in <hi>Ezek.</hi> 43. they are exhorted to put away their whoredoms and abominations which had de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>filed God's holy Name; ſo ought all that are called Chriſtians to put away ſuch things that defile God's Name. You may ſee how the Lord forbids Adultery in <hi>Levit.</hi> 20. and you may ſee what Judgments came upon <hi>Iſrael,</hi> who committed Adultery with the Children of <hi>Moab;</hi> and how the Lord brought his Judgments upon <hi>Iſrael,</hi> and them that they committed Adul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tery withal, as in <hi>Numb.</hi> 25. for the Lord ſaid and command<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, <hi>That there ſhould be no whore of the daughters of Iſrael, nor a Sodomite of the Sons of Iſrael,</hi> Deut. 23. Then ſurely there ought not to be a whore, nor a <hi>Sodomite</hi> amongſt them that are called Chriſtians; but when either Jews, Chriſtians, or others, rebels againſt God's good Spirit he hath given to in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruct them, then they run into whoredoms and adultery, and are as bad as the <hi>Sodomites,</hi> and profane the Name of God and his Son Chriſt Jeſus.</p>
            <p>And what became of <hi>Jezabel,</hi> and all her Prieſts, who was called, <hi>The Mother of Whoredoms and Witchcraft,</hi> as in 2 <hi>Kings</hi> 9.22. Did not her whoredoms, and her bloo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:47472:7"/>Spirit, act together in wickedneſs and blood-ſhedding.</p>
            <p>And the Lord ſent <hi>Nahum</hi> to declare againſt <hi>Nineveh,</hi> and the miſery and ruin thereof, and ſaith, <hi>Wo to the bloody City, it is full of lies and Robbery, and therefore becauſe of the multitude of the whoredoms of the well-favoured Harlot, the Miſtreſs of Witch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>craft, that ſelleth Nations through her whoredom, and Fami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lies through her Witchcraft. Behold, I am againſt thee, ſaith the Lord of Hoſt, and I will diſcover thy Skirts upon thy face. I will ſhew the Nations thy nakedneſs, and the Kingdoms thy ſhame, and I will caſt abominable filth upon thee, and make thee vile; and will ſet thee as a gazing ſtock, and all they that look upon thee ſhall fly from thee, and ſay, Nineveh is laid waſte,</hi> Nahum. 3. Now <hi>Nineveh</hi> had repented at <hi>Jonahs</hi> Preaching; but ſee what whoredoms and wickedneſs ſhe was run into, which brought her deſtruction; and therefore let all that go un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>r the name of Chriſtians, take heed of ſuch evils, leſt they bring Judgments and deſtruction, and ruin upon themſelves.</p>
            <p>And <hi>Jacob</hi>'s ſons were not able to bear nor endure that <hi>She<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chem</hi> ſhould raviſh or defile their ſiſter <hi>Dinah,</hi> Gen. 34 that they <hi>ſhould deal with their Siſter as with a Harlot;</hi> and it grived them, and they were wroth, becauſe he had wrought folly in <hi>Iſrael,</hi> and therefore that folly is to be kept out of Chriſtendom.</p>
            <p>And <hi>Joſeph</hi> who was tempted by his Miſtreſs the <hi>Egyptian</hi> Woman, though he was her bought Slave and her Captive, yet <hi>Joſeph</hi> ſaid unto her, <hi>How then can I do this great wicked<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, and ſin againſt my God,</hi> Gen. 39. But as <hi>David</hi> ſaid God ordained in <hi>Joſeph</hi> a Teſtimony againſt ſuch wicked things; when <hi>Joſeph</hi> was in <hi>Egypt,</hi> and God eſtabliſhed a Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtimony in <hi>Jacob,</hi> and <hi>Joſeph</hi> ſucceeded him in the Teſtimony of God, <hi>Pſal.</hi> 78. &amp; 5.81. &amp; 5. for <hi>David</hi> ſaith, <hi>He eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſhed a Teſtimony in Jacob, and appointed a Law in Iſrael.</hi> (Mark) In which he commanded their Fathers that they ſhould make them known to their Children, that the Genera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion to come might know them, even the Children which ſhould be born, who ſhould riſe and declare them to their Children, that they might ſet their hopes upon God, and not forget the works of God, but keep his Commandments: ſo all that keeps this Law and Teſtimony of God in their hearts will teſtifie
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:47472:7"/>againſt all ſuch evils before mentioned, and judge them.</p>
            <p>And the Scribes and Phariſees ſaid unto Chriſt, in <hi>Mat.</hi> 12. <hi>We would ſee a ſign of thee;</hi> and Chriſt ſaid unto them, <hi>An evil and adulterous Generation ſeeks after a Sign, but thereſhall be no Sign given to it but the ſign of the Prophet Jonas. For as Jonas was three daies and three nights in the Whales bel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly: ſo ſhall the ſon of man be three daies and three nights in the heart of the Earth.</hi> Here is a ſign for the evil and adulterons Generation, who rebels againſt the good Spirit that God hath given to inſtruct them, that with his Spirit they might ſee Chriſt the ſubſtance of all Signs; and Chriſt ſaid, <hi>Whoſoever therefore ſhall be aſhamed of me, and of my words, in this adul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terous and ſinful Generation; of him alſo ſhall the Son of man be aſhamed when he cometh in the Glory of his Father, with his holy Angels,</hi> Mark 8. &amp; 38. So we muſt not be aſhamed to confeſs the truth before an adulterous Generation that are adulterated from the Truth; <hi>Know ye not,</hi> ſaith the Apoſtle, <hi>That the unrighteous ſhall not inherit the Kingdom of God. Be not deceived, neither Fornicators, nor Idolaters, nor Adulte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rers, nor abuſers of themſelves with mankind, nor Thieves, nor Covetous, nor Drunkards, nor Revilers, nor Extortioners, ſhall inherit the Kingdom of God,</hi> 1 Cor. 6. Now they that do think that ſuch as lives in theſe Evils, ſhall inherit the Kingdom of God, they are deceived. And again, the Apoſtle ſaith to the <hi>Galatians, Now,</hi> ſaith he, <hi>the works of the fleſh are mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſt, which are theſe, Adultery, Fornication, <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ncleanneſs, La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſciviouſneſs, Idolatry, Witchcraft, Hatred, Variance, Wrath, Strife, Sedition, Hereſie, Envyings, Murders, Drunkenneſs, Revilings,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>of which I tell you before, as I have alſo told you in times paſt, that they which do ſuch things, ſhall not inhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit the Kingdom of God,</hi> Gal. 5. Therefore they are deceived that live in ſuch things, and thinks they ſhall inherit the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom of God; and the Apoſtle ſaith, <hi>Your bodies are the mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers of Chriſt,</hi> ſpeaking to the <hi>Corinthians,</hi> and he bids them <hi>Fly Fornication; Every ſin that a man doth, is without the body: but he that commits Fornication, ſins againſt his own body,</hi> as well as againſt the Lord's Law and Goſpel, and therefore <hi>ye are bought with a price: glorifie God in your bodies, and in your Spirits, which are Gods,</hi> 1 Cor. 6.</p>
            <pb n="10" facs="tcp:47472:8"/>
            <p>And the Apoſtle tells the <hi>Epheſians</hi> in the 5.3. <hi>But Fornicati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on and all uncleannoſs; or coveteouſneſs, let it not be named amongſt you, as becometh Saints: neither filthineſs; nor fooliſh talking, nor jeſting, which are not convenient: but rather giving of thanks. For this ye know, that no whoremonger, nor unclean perſon, nor coveteous man who is an Idolater, hath any inheritance in the Kingdom of Chriſt, and of God; Let no man deceive you with vain words: for becauſe of theſe things cometh the wrath of God upon the diſobedient; be not ye therefore par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>takers,</hi> to wit, in ſuch things before mentioned, for they that live in and practice ſuch abominable things, before mentioned, and to think to have an inheritance in the Kingdom of Chriſt and of God, where no unclean thing enters, they deceive them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, <hi>Therefore let us caſt off the works of darkneſs, and put on the armour of light, let us all walk honeſtly</hi> (to wit) true Chriſtians) <hi>as in the day; not in rioting and drunkenneſs, not in chambering and wantonneſs, not in ſtrife and envy; but put ye on the Lord Jeſus Chriſt, and make no proviſion for the fleſh, to fulfil the luſts thereof,</hi> Rom. 13.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>James</hi> ſaith in Chap. 4. <hi>Ye luſt, and have not: ye kill and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire to have, and cannot obtain: ye fight and war, yet ye have not, ye ask and receive not, becauſe ye ask amiſs, that ye may conſume it upon your own Luſts. Ye adulterers, and adultereſſes, know ye not that the friendſhip of this world is enmity with God? whoſoever therefore will be a friend of this world, is the enemy of God;</hi> and therefore all you that go under the name of Chri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtians; conſider to whom ye are enemies, and with whom ye have friendſhip.</p>
            <p>And in 2 <hi>Pet.</hi> 2. he ſhews how God ſpared not the Angels that ſinned, nor he ſpared not the old World that ſinned, but brought a flood upon the World of ungodly, and ſaved <hi>Noah,</hi> &amp;c. the Preacher of Righteouſneſs; and God turned the Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties of <hi>Sodom</hi> and <hi>Gomorrah</hi> into aſhes, and condemned and overthrew them for their ſin, wickedneſs and ungodlineſs, making them an example unto all thoſe that after ſhould live ungodly, and delivered juſt <hi>Lot,</hi> vexed with the filthy converſation of the wicked, for that righteous man dwelling amongſt them, in ſee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and hearing, vext his righteous ſoul from day to day with their unlawful deeds.</p>
            <pb n="11" facs="tcp:47472:8"/>
            <p>And now is not ſpiritual <hi>Sodom,</hi> which makes a great profeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of the Old and New Teſtament, as great a grief to the righteous ſouls, who hears and ſees their unlawful deeds? And the Apoſtle ſaw in this day ſuch as had forſaken the right way, which were as natural bruit Beaſts, and ſhould periſh in their own corruption, and ſhall receive the reward of unrighteouſneſs, as they which count it pleaſure to riot in the day time, ſpots they are and blemiſhes, ſporting themſelves with their own de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceivings, while they feaſt with you; ſo the Apoſtle hath mark'd them to be known by their ſpots and blemiſhes, <hi>having eyes full of adultery,</hi> that cannot ceaſe from ſin, beguiling unſtable ſouls, a heart they have exerciſed with coveteous practices. Curſed Children; ſo their hearts were not only full of Adultery, but the Apoſtle could ſee that their very eyes were full of Adultery; and ſo is it with the ſame ſpirit now. Such who have forſaken Chriſt the right way; theſe are Wells which have no water in them, and Clouds which are carried about with a Tempeſt, to whom the miſt of darkneſs is reſerved for ever: ſo Clouds ye know are high, and ye know what the Tempeſt is; ſo they are known by the Tempeſt, that is, in their Spirit, and their Clouds and their great ſwelling words of vanity, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Theſe are they that promiſe liberty, and themſelves ſervants of corruption, and they that are overcome by them are brought into bondage, and it is better for ſuch never to have known the way of righte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ouſneſs, then after they have known, to turn from the holy Commandment; but it is happened unto them <hi>the Dog is turned to his vomit, and the Sow to the wallowing in the mire.</hi> And are not the days of Scoffers come, which walk after their own un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>godly luſts, and not after Chriſt. You may ſee how the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtles eſpecially <hi>Paul, Peter, James, John</hi> and <hi>Jude</hi> bore a Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtimony againſt all manner of looſeneſs, and ſuch who had known the Truth, and run into evil, that <hi>their latter end would be worſe than their beginning.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>And you may ſee in <hi>Rev.</hi> 17. the mother of all abomination, <hi>A woman arrayed in purple and Scarlet, with a golden Cup in her hand, ſitting upon the Beaſt, which is great Babilon, the mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther of Harlots,</hi> who harloted from God's good Spirit; this mother of Harlots is the abomination of the Earth, which is drunk with the blood of the Saints and Martyrs of Jeſus. This
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:47472:9"/>woman the falſe Church, who is whored from the Spirit of God, which is drunk with the blood of the Martyrs and Saints. He doth ſay, <hi>She is drunk with Wine,</hi> only this drunken Whore is mad and in a rage and fury for the blood of the Saints. But what becomes of her in the end, is not ſhe burnt in the fire? and the Beaſt, falſe Prophets and the Devil? and the Lamb and the Saints will have the victory over them; and this great Whore or falſe Church, who is whored from the Spirit of God, is the Spirit of all them that be harloted from the Spirit of God in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the evil deſtroying. And all thoſe that are led by the Spirit of God, they are of the woman the true Church that is in God, and are of the Church of the Firſt-born, which are written in heaven and heavenly <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> that is above, is their mother, and they ſing <hi>Hallelujah, and Glory, and Honour, and Praiſes to the Lord God, for true righteouſneſs are his Judgments; for he Judgeth the great whore which corrupted the earth with her Forni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation, and hath avenged the blood of his Servants at her hand, Hal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lelujah,</hi> Rev. 19. And in <hi>Rev.</hi> 18. you may ſee what great lamentations are from the high and low (to wit) the harlots which ſee the down-fall of their Mother the whore, who is whored and harloted from the Spirit of God, what crying and ſaying, <hi>Alas, alas,</hi> there is; and what rejoycing of the Apo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtles and the Prophets, yea, the very Heaven rejoyceth at the down-fal of this whore, yea whoriſh Spirit, and falſe Church, for in her was found the blood of the Prophets and Saints, and all that were ſlain upon the earth, hath been found in this who<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh ſpirit, who have whored from the Spirit of God and the Lamb.</p>
            <p>And in <hi>Rev.</hi> 21. he ſaith, <hi>He that overcometh ſhall inherit all things, and I will be his God, and he ſhall be my ſon. But the fearful and unbelieving, and the abominable, and murderers, and whoremongers, and ſorcerers, and Idolaters, and all lyars ſhall have their part in the Lake which burns with fire and brimſtone, which is the ſecond death.</hi> Whoſoever is not found written in the book of Life, is to be caſt into the Lake of Fire; and therefore what good will all your profeſſion do in Chriſtendom, if ye be found in theſe ſins and evils before mentioned, and your names not written in the Lambs Book of Life before the foundation of the World; for they that have right to the tree of Life, walk in
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:47472:9"/>the light of the Lamb, and believe in it; ſuch are they that en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters in through the Gate into the heavenly City New <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> and have their fathers name written in their fore heads, <hi>For without</hi> this holy City new <hi>Jeruſalem are Dogs,</hi> biters of the Lambs of Chriſt, <hi>and Sorcerers, and whoremongers, and mur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derers, idolaters, and whoſoever loveth and maketh a lye;</hi> all ſuch deceivers, and defilers, and corrupters of themſelves and others, are without the holy City of God new <hi>Jeruſalem, Rev.</hi> 22. <hi>For whoremongers and Idolaters God will judge,</hi> Heb. 13 4. And therefore all that love God and his Son, is to judge ſuch evils, and turn from them (before mentioned) if you will come into favour with God; and here you may ſee what wickedneſs hath been all along, and in all Ages ſince man and woman fell from the Image of God; and amongſt ſuch that rebel againſt God's good Spirit which he hath given them in the time of the Law. And God pours out of his Spirit upon all fleſh in this Goſpel-day; and all ſuch as rebel againſt this good Spirit of God, what Idolatry and other evils, whoredoms, Adulteries and Fornications are amongſt them, who, as I ſaid before, do rebel againſt God's good Spirit, which grieves the Lord and his righteous People, for which God will Judge. And ſuch as acts ſuch things before mentioned, and lives in them, the Lord tells them, They ſhall not enter into his Kingdom, nor into his holy City <hi>New Jeruſalem,</hi> for no unclean thing comes into his holy City, or holy Kingdom, for they that come into this holy City or Kingdom, muſt be made clean with the blood of the Lamb.</p>
            <p>And what became of <hi>Adam</hi> and <hi>Eve</hi> who diſobeyed the Lord, were they not turned out of Paradice, the Garden of God, the Garden of pleaſures, into the earth.</p>
            <p>And what became of the Old World, who diſobeyed and grieved the Lord's Spirit? did not the Lord bring a Flood up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on them, and deſtroy them all? who ſaved righteous <hi>Noah</hi> and his Family.</p>
            <p>And what became of <hi>Nimrod,</hi> that mighty hunter before the Lord, and them that followed him; did not the Lord ſay, <hi>No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thing will be reſtrained from them which they imagined to do;</hi> and ſo the Lord confounded them, and ſcattered them abroad from <hi>Babel,</hi> upon the face of all the Earth, <hi>Gen.</hi> 11. This was the fruits of them that followed their imaginations, and not the Lord and his Spirit.</p>
            <pb n="14" facs="tcp:47472:10"/>
            <p>And what became of <hi>Sodom</hi> and <hi>Gemorrah</hi> for their wickedneſs and filthineſs? did not the Lord deſtroy them and their Cities by fire, and ſaved juſt <hi>Lot?</hi> Gen. 19.</p>
            <p>And what became of the Jews, to wit, the houſe of <hi>Iſrael?</hi> and the Houſe of <hi>Judah?</hi> who rebelled againſt God's good Spirit, who diſobey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed the Lord, and perſecuted his Prophets, who went early and late to warn them of the Judgments that would come upon them, but they nei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther regarded the Lord nor his Prophets? Did not the Lord bring the Heathen upon them, which carried them out of their own Land which flowed with Milk and Honey, into Captivity under the Heathen, in which nature they were gone into, who rebelled againſt God and his Spirit. And what became of the Jews after they came again into their land, who rebelled againſt Chriſt and cryed up <hi>Caeſar,</hi> and Crucified Chriſt, and perſecuted his Apoſtles; and did not Chriſt ſay, <hi>T<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>at their Temple ſh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>uld be thrown down, and the City compaſſed about with Armies, and the Jews ſcattered over all Nations?</hi> And did not this come to paſs after Chriſt was riſen? And did not the Jews alſo rebel againſt <hi>Titus,</hi> when he came to beſiege <hi>Jeruſalem?</hi> ſo they did not only rebel againſt Chriſt, but re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>belled againſt the Heathen at laſt; and what became of them but deſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ction and calamity, who under a pretence of worſhipping God and crying up the Temple, and outward <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> and making an outward profeſſion of the Old Teſtament, but reſiſted the Holy Ghoſt, and rebelled againſt God's good Spirit, and his Son Chriſt Jeſus, in their deceitful hypocri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tical profeſſion, and living in Idolatry, and Spiritual, and carnal whore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom and Adultery.</p>
            <p>And what becometh of the falſe Prophets, and Beaſt of the Whore, and all her Harlots that is whored and harlo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ed from the Spirit of God, muſt not they all have their end in the Lake of fire that burns with brimſtone with the Devil, the God of the world, and the Prince of the Air, who rules in the hearts of the Children of diſobedience, that diſobeys God and his good Spirit.</p>
            <p>And the Prince of the Air makes many Fowls of the Air with his ſoul airy ſpirit, by his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#MURP" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>oul air in whom he rules, and he is the Ruler in all the Children of the diſobedient, which diſobey God's good Spirit, he rules in them with his a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ry unclean ſpirit, who blinds the diſobedient with his duſt and air; for duſt is his meat, who is out of the Truth, and abode not in it, in whom there is no Truth; and all that diſobey the holy Spirit of the Lamb, are his followers and ſubjects; and he in whom there is no truth, rules in them, who is the author of all ſin, cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruption and darkneſs, whoſe end is in the Lake of fire that burns with Brimſtone, and his Followers; but the chaſt Virgins follow the Lamb, and they that are led by the Spirit of God, are the ſons of God, and walk in the truth, and <hi>worſhip God in Spirit and Truth;</hi> his truth is over the head of the Devil, and he is out of it, and cannot get into it, for there is no truth in him, and therefore he and his Followers are not like to get into the Truth, that Gods Children worſhip God in.</p>
            <trailer>THE END</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:47472:10"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
